Daniel Yankelovich Papers
© 2002 University of Connecticut
- Series II: Projects,1949-1994
  - Subseries B: Nuclear Policy Projects,undated, 1969-1990
    - Related Nuclear Material
      - Books, journal issues and reports
        - Bobbitt, Philip Chase, United States Nuclear Strategy: the Problem of Extended Deterrence - Ph.D. dissertation, 1983 (Box 42:973-976)
        - Bogdanov, Radomir, The U.S. War Machine and Politics, 1986 (Box 42:977)
        - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists,, vol. 39, no. 4, 1983 Apr (Box 42:978)
        - Clark, D., U.S. Foreign Policy: Adjusting to Change in The Third World, 1985 (Box 42:979)
        - Clark, D., United States - Soviet Relations: Building a Congressional Cadre, 1986 (Box 42:980)
        - Clark, D., United States - Soviet Relations: Building a Consensus Policy, 1985 (Box 42:981)
        - Clausen, P., A. Krass, and R. Zirkle, In Search of Stability: An Assessment of New U.S. Nuclear Forces, 1986 (Box 42:982)
        - The Commission on Integrated Long-term Strategy, Discriminated Deterrence, 1988 (Box 42:983)
        - Committee for National Security, Mission Impossible? An Illustrated Guide to Defense Planning in the 1990s, 1989 (Box 43:984)
        - Congressional Roundtable on U.S-Soviet Relations - 1986 Report, 1986 (Box 43:985)
        - Countdown on SALT II, 1985 (Box 43:986)
        - Dahrendorf, R. and T. Sorensen, A Widening Atlantic? Domestic Change & Foreign Policy - draft, 1986 (Box 43:987)
        - Defense Budget Task Force, Restructuring The U.S. Military: Defense Needs in the 21st Century, 1990 (Box 43:988)
        - The Economist, vol. 296, no. 74051985 Aug 9 (Box 43:989)
        - Esposito, L. and J. Shear, The Command and Control of Nuclear Weapons, 1985 (Box 43:990)
        - Esquire, vol. 97, no. 3, 1982 Mar (Box 43:991)
        - Forsberg, R. and R. Leavitt, Alternative Defense - draft, 1987 (Box 43:992)
        - Graham, Daniel, We Must Defend America, 1983 (Box 43:993)
        - Hartung, W., R. DeGrasse, and R. Nimroody, The Strategic Defense Initiative: Cost Contractors and Consequences, 1985 (Box 43:994)
        - Hoffman, S. and C. Vance, Building the Peace: U.S. Foreign Policy for the Next Decade, 1982 (Box 43:995)
        - Hubert H. Humphrey Institute of Public Affairs, Waging Peace: Working Together on National Security and Arms Control, [1985] (Box 43:996)
        - Institute for East-West Security Studies, How Should America Respond to Gorbachev's Challenge?, 1987 (Box 43:997)
        - Longstreth, Thomas, The Impact of U.S. and Soviet Ballistic Missile Defense Programs on the ABM Treaty, 1985 (Box 43:998)
        - Louis Harris and Associates, The Playboy Report on American Men, 1979 (Box 43:999)
        - Lynch, Allen C., Confidence-Building in the 1980s - A Conference Report, 1985 (Box 43:1000)
        - McNamara, K., Approaches to Arms Control in Europe - A Conference Report, 1985 (Box 43:1001)
        - Miller, W. and J. Petrocik, Where is the Party? An Assessment of Changes in Party Loyalty and Party Coalition in the 1980s, 1987 (Box 43:1002)
        - National Academy of Sciences, Reykjavik and Beyond, 1988 (Box 43:1003)
        - National Journal, no. 43, 1983 Oct 22 (Box 43:1004)
        - The New Republic, issues 3547 and 3548, 1983 Jan 10, 17 (Box 43:1005)
        - Nuclear Times
          - Volume 1, nos. 6, 8, 9, 1983 Apr, Jun, Jul (Box 43:1006)
          - Volume 2, nos. 1, 2, 1983 Oct, Nov/Dec (Box 43:1007)
          - Volume 2, nos. 3, 4, 1984 Jan, Feb (Box 44:1008)
          - Volume 2, nos. 7, 8, 1984 Jun, Jul (Box 44:1009)
          - Volume 2, no. 10, Volume 3, no. 4, 1984 Sep, 1985 Mar (Box 44:1010)
          - Volume 3, no. 6, Volume 4, no. 1, 1985 May/Jun, Sep/Oct (Box 44:1011)
        - Proceedings of the Symposium 'The Role of the Academy in Addressing the Issues of Nuclear War', 1982 (Box 44:1012)
        - Public Opinion, vol. 2, no. 3, 1979 Jun/Jul (Box 44:1013)
        - Report, by International Physicians for the Prevention of Nuclear War, Inc. (IPPNW)
          - Volume 2, no. 3, 1984 Oct (Box 44:1014)
          - Volume 4, no. 1, 1986 Feb (Box 44:1015)
        - Research and Forecasts, Inc., Peace Media Project Summary of Public Opinion on Nuclear Arms, 1984 (Box 44:1016)
        - Rules of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union, 1986 (Box 44:1017)
        - Sherr, A.B., The European Nuclear Negotiations: Paths to War or Peace?, 1983 (Box 44:1018)
        - Sorensen, Theodore, "The 'Widening Atlantic': Societal Changes and Foreign Policy" - draft, 1985 (Box 44:1019)
        - Strategy for Peace 1983 - The Stanley Foundation U.S. Foreign Policy Conference Report, 1983 (Box 44:1020)
        - Soumen Kuvalehti - The Finnish Newsmagazine, 1987 Jun 18 (Box 44:1021)
        - USA Economics, Politics, Ideology (in Russian) no. 12, 1989 Dec (Box 44:1022)
        - U.S. Department of State, Bureau of Public Affairs, Security and Arms Control: The Search for a More Stable Peace, 1984 (Box 44:1023)
        - Zacharias, J., M. Gordon and S. Davis, Common Sense and Nuclear Peace, 1983 (Box 44:1024)
      - Papers
        - The Arms Control Association, "Star Wars: An Anthology of Quotes by the Administration, Congress, and Outside Experts", 1985 (Box 44:1025)
        - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, "A Comprehensive East-West Agenda", undated (Box 44:1026)
        - Becker, Abraham S., "Issues in U.S.-Soviet Economic Relations", 1984 (Box 44:1027)
        - Bethe, Hans and Robert McNamara, "Reducing the Risk of Nuclear War: Geneva Can be a Step Toward a More Secure 21st Century" - draft, 1985 (Box 44:1028)
        - Bialer, Seweryn, "Andropov's Burden: Socialist Stagnation and Communist Encirclement", 1983 (Box 44:1029)
        - Birnbaum, Norman, "A New Foreign Policy: A Political Mirage", 1985 (Box 44:1030)
        - Birnbaum, Norman, "The United States, The Peace Movement, and the Two Europes", 1983 (Box 44:1031)
        - Blockwill, Robert D., "European Influences and Constraints on U.S. Policy Toward the Soviet Union", 1984 (Box 44:1032)
        - Blakely, Allison, "Soviet History and World View", undated (Box 44:1033)
        - Cain, Stephen, "The FY 1990/91 Defense Budget Preliminary Analysis", 1989 (Box 44:1034)
        - Casper, Barry and Lawrence Krauss, "Fortune Favors the Prepared Mind: A Movement Against Nuclear War" - draft, [1981] (Box 44:1035)
        - Chayes, Antonia, "Europe: The Hamlet of Arms Control?", 1985 (Box 45:1036)
        - "Economic, Diplomatic, and Strategic Factors Affecting The U.S. Relationship with Western Europe", 1984 (Box 45:1037)
        - Ellsberg, Daniel, "Implications of Public Opinion Polls for Freeze Strategy", 1985 (Box 45:1038)
        - Ezekiel, Raphael, "Nuclear War and Denial: First Data", 1983 (Box 45:1039)
        - Farago, Istvan, "No-First-Use A Window of Opportunity", 1985 (Box 45:1040)
        - Forsberg, Randall, "Non- provocative Defense: A New Approach to Arms Control", 1986 (Box 45:1041)
        - Fukumoto, Matsuo, "To Avoid A Nuclear War", 1985 (Box 45:1042)
        - Fukuyama, Francis, "U.S.- Soviet Interactions in the Third World", 1984 (Box 45:1043)
        - Gellner, Charles, "Soviet Compliance with the SALT I and II Agreements on Offensive Arms", 1985 (Box 45:1044)
        - Gellner, Charles, "The U.S. Arms Control and Disarmament Agency: Data on Management, Personnel, Budget, Status and Related Matters, 1981-83", 1984 (Box 45:1045)
        - Gelman, Harry, "The Rise and Fall of Détente: Lessons for the Two Elites", 1984 (Box 45:1046)
        - Gelman, Harry, "The Rise and Fall of Détente: Causes and Consequences", 1985 (Box 45:1047)
        - Hoagland, Jim, "The Role of Summitry in Superpower Relations: An American View", 1988 (Box 45:1048)
        - Horelick, Arnold and Edward Warner, III, "U.S.-Soviet Nuclear Arms Control: The Next Phase", 1984 (Box 45:1049)
        - Hough, Jerry, "Soviet Options Toward the West", 1985 (Box 45:1050)
        - Hyland, William G., "The Soviet Dimension", undated (Box 45:1051)
        - Hyland, William G., "The U.S. and U.S.S.R.: Rebuilding Relations", 1984 (Box 45:1052)
        - Joffe, Josef, "The Political Role of Nuclear Weapons: No-First-Use and the Stability of the European Order", 1985 (Box 45:1053)
        - "The Political Role of Nuclear Weapons: No-First-Use and the Stability of the European Order", [1982] (Box 45:1054)
        - Kalicki, Jan H., "Nuclear Dilemmas in Moscow", undated (Box 45:1055)
        - Korbonski, Andrzej, "Eastern Europe and U.S.-Soviet Relations", 1984 (Box 45:1056)
        - Larrabee, F. Stephen and Allen Lynch, "Confidence-Building Measures and U.S.-Soviet Relations", 1986 (Box 45:1057)
        - Lee, John M., "The Use of Nuclear Weapons", 1984 (Box 45:1058)
        - Mendelbaum, Michael, "The Soviet Economy in Crisis", 1991 (Box 45:1059)
        - Marttila, John, "Democrats, U.S.-Soviet Relations and National Security", 1988 (Box 45:1060)
        - Nye, Joseph, "The Domestic Environment of U.S. Policy Making", 1984 (Box 45:1061)
        - Nye, Joseph", Ethics and Foreign Policy", 1985 (Box 45:1062)
        - Pipes, Richard, "Survival Is Not Enough", 1984 (Box 45:1063)
        - Plous, Scott, "Overcoming Psychological and Strategic Barriers in Present Attempts at Nuclear Disarmament: A New Proposal", 1984 (Box 45:1064)
        - Plous, Scott, "Perceptual Illusions and Military Realities: A Social-Psychological Analysis of the Nuclear Arms Race", undated (Box 45:1065)
        - Remington, R. A., "From Empire to Alliance: The Dynamics of the Soviet-East European Relationship", 1985 (Box 45:1066)
        - Rowen, Henry, "The Pivotal and Neglected Role of Eastern Europe in the Defense Policy of the West", 1985 (Box 45:1067)
        - Rusk, Dean, "Rethinking National Security and Arms Control", undated (Box 45:1068)
        - Saunders, Harold, "The Dartmouth Conference and the Middle East", undated (Box 45:1069)
        - Shulman, Marshall, "A Citizen's Approach to Soviet-American Relations", 1984 (Box 46:1070)
        - Shulman, Marshall, "The Next Phase: Alternative Frameworks for Managing U.S.-Soviet Relations", 1984 (Box 46:1071)
        - Simes, Dimitri, "The Domestic Environment of Soviet Policymaking", 1984 (Box 46:1072)
        - Somerville, John, "Mutual No-First-Use or Mutual Suicide?", 1984 (Box 46:1073)
        - Stewart, Philip, "Gorbachev and Détente: Towards National Self-Reliance?", [1986] (Box 46:1074)
        - Stewart, Philip, "Toward Isolationism?: Soviet Policy Perspectives After Brezhnev", 1985 (Box 46:1075)
        - Suny, Ronald, "Soviet Foreign Policy Aims in the Nuclear Age", undated (Box 46:1076)
        - "The Swedish Nuclear Referendum 1980", [1980] (Box 46:1077)
        - Talbott, Strobe, "U.S.-Soviet Nuclear Arms Control: Where We Are and How We Got There", 1985 (Box 46:1078)
        - Winik, Jay, "Beyond Deterrence", 1986 (Box 46:1079)
        - Yankelovich, Nicole, "Possibilities for Peace: The Nuclear Dilemma", 1982 (Box 46:1080)
        - "Possibilities for Peace: The Nuclear Dilemma", 1983 (Box 46:1081)
        - Yost, Charles, "National and Collective Responsibility", 1981 (Box 46:1082)
      - Speeches and Presentations
        - Aspin, Les, "The 1986 Defense Budget - A Democratic Program", 1985 May 30 (Box 46:1083)
        - Aspin, Les, "A Democratic Defense Policy: Defense Without Nonsense", 1985 Apr 17 (Box 46:1084)
        - Audiguier, Pierre, "East-West Relations", 1984 Nov 9 (Box 46:1085)
        - Bialer, Seweryn, "The Psychology of U.S.- Soviet Relations", 1983 Apr 14 (Box 46:1086)
        - Bialer, Seweryn, presentation concerning U.S.- Soviet relations, undated (Box 46:1087)
        - Caldwell, Dan, lecture on the nuclear freeze movement, 1982 Oct 9 (Box 46:1088)
        - Friedman, Thomas, "The Lessons of Lebanon: A Personal Retrospective", 1984 Sep 17 (Box 46:1089)
        - Gillies, Archibald, "Post-Reagan America", 1986 May 9 (Box 46:1090)
        - Gorbachev, Mikhail, statement, 1986 Jan 15 (Box 46:1091)
        - Hughes, Thomas L., "Reagan, Foreign Policy and the Strange Death of Liberal America", 1984 Jun 19 (Box 46:1092)
        - Kassebaum, Nancy Landon, speech before the Arms Control Association, 1985 Dec 3 (Box 46:1093)
        - Kennan, George F., "A Proposal for International Disarmament", 1981 May 19 (Box 46:1094)
        - Morrison, Philip, lecture no. 3, "Strategic Issues": notes, 1986 Mar 20 (Box 46:1095)
        - Nobel Peace Prize Speeches and Lectures, 1985, 1986 (Box 46:1096)
        - Pym, Francis, "The Strategic Defense Initiative: A European View", 1985 Nov 8 (Box 46:1097)
        - Rohatyn, Felix, address to the Citizen Exchange Council, 1987 Oct 26 (Box 46:1098)
        - Smoke, Richard, Commencement Forum Talk: notes, 1985 May 25 (Box 46:1099)
        - Stanley, C. Maxwell, "Forging a Strategy for Peace", 1983 Oct (Box 46:1100)
        - Watson, Thomas J., "Can the American Political System Adapt to the Nuclear Era?", 1986 Apr 25 (Box 46:1101)
        - Weinberger, Caspar, "Facing the Challenge of Arms Reduction", 1984 Nov 15 (Box 46:1102)
        - Von Straden, Berndt, "Where Do We Go From Here?: Détente - Between Skepticism and Hope", 1984 Feb 9 (Box 46:1103)
        - Von Weisacker, Richard, speech during a 40th anniversary commemoration of the end of World War II and Nazism, 1985 May 8 (Box 46:1104)
      - Conferences
        - Arms control seminar, Harvard: notes,1984 Nov 7 (Box 46:1105)
        - Arms control seminar, Harvard: notes,1985 Apr 23-24 (Box 46:1106)
        - Aspen/WYE Communications Conference: notes,1985 Jun 5-9 (Box 46:1107)
        - "Avoiding Nuclear War," faculty seminar: minutes,1986 Mar 12 (Box 46:1108)
        - "Beyond Deterrence," workshop: notes,1986 Feb 22 (Box 46:1109)
        - Brown University presentation: notes,1986 Sep (Box 46:1110)
        - "Conference on U.S.-Soviet Relations: The Next Phase",1984 Oct 18-19 (Box 46:1111)
        - Council on Foreign Relations Roundtable meetings: notes,1983-1988 (Box 47:1112-1113)
        - Discussion group on national security issues,1984 Feb 10 (Box 47:1114)
        - Exploratory meeting concerning the nuclear deadlock,1983 Mar 20-22 (Box 47:1115)
        - Exploratory meeting concerning the nuclear deadlock: notes,1983 Mar 20-23 (Box 47:1116-1117)
        - Institute for East-West Security breakfast meeting,1986 Feb 19 (Box 47:1118)
        - Miscellaneous conferences and presentations,undated, 1982-1987 (Box 47:1119)
        - "Prospects for Nuclear Arms Control - Hope or Reality?",1984 Mar 13 (Box 47:1120)
        - RAND Conference: notes,1984 Oct 18 (Box 47:1121)
      - Subject Files
        - Arms Control Association,1983-1985 (Box 47:1122)
        - The Aspen Institute Preparatory Group, "East-West Relations: Past, Present and Future", 1984 (Box 47:1123)
        - Attitudes toward the Soviet Union, 1983 (Box 47:1124)
        - Book chapters: miscellaneous, undated,1987 (Box 47:1125)
        - Bureau of Public Affairs, Current Policy issues, undated, 1982-1985 (Box 47:1126)
        - House Armed Service Committee reports, nos. 25, 26, 1987 Jan, Feb (Box 47:1127)
        - Congressional Record excerpts, 1984, 1988 (Box 47:1128)
        - The Independent Commission on Disarmament and Security Issues: statement, 1984 Dec 2 (Box 47:1129)
        - Institute of East-West Security Studies, 1985-1987 (Box 47:1130)
        - Institute for Soviet-American Relations, 1984 (Box 47:1131)
        - Institute for World Order, 1982 (Box 47:1132)
        - Miscellaneous, 1982-1983 (Box 47:1133)
        - News show transcripts, 1981, 1985-1986 (Box 48:1134)
        - Newsletters, 1981-1987 (Box 48:1135)
        - Nuclear freeze campaign, 1982-1984 (Box 48:1136)
        - Public opinion polls, 1983-1985 (Box 48:1137)
        - Reading lists, 1981-1982 (Box 48:1138)
        - Russian language learning materials, undated, 1975 (Box 48:1139)
        - Solms, Friedhelm, ed., Heidelberg Peace Memorandum, undated (Box 48:1140)
        - Soviet journal, New World (in Russian), 1985 (Box 48:1141)
        - Soviet journal, "New World" (in Russian), 1985 (Box 48:1142)
        - Soviet public opinion polls, 1991 (Box 48:1143-1144)
        - START negotiations, 1984 (Box 48:1145)
        - U.S. - Soviet survey data, 1985-1986 (Box 48:1146)
        - U.S. - Soviet joint public opinion projects, 1985-1987 (Box 48:1147)
        - Union of Concerned Scientists, 1982 (Box 48:1148)
        - World Policy Institute, 1984, 1990 (Box 48:1149)
      - Journal articles, 1969, 1980-1982 (Box 48:1150-1152)
      - Journal articles, undated, 1983-1988 (Box 49:1153-1158)
      - Reprinted articles, 1982-1987 (Box 49:1159-1161)
  - Subseries C: Work Projects, undated, 1958-1990
    - Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 49:1162)
    - Jobs in the 1980s: Bridging the Gap Between People and Work
      - Project proposal, 1979 Jan 30 (Box 49:1163)
      - Quality of employment survey: data printouts, 1977 (Box 49:1164-1165)
      - Jobs in the Eighties Survey, American sample: data printouts, 1982 (Box 49:1166-1167)
      - Jobs in the Eighties Survey, American sample: data printouts, 1982 (Box 50:1168-1177)
      - Jobs in the 1980s International Survey, Volume II: The Research Report, 1983 (Box 50:1178-1185)
      - Jobs in the 1980s International Survey: Demographic Tables, Part 1, 1983 (Box 51:1186-1187)
      - Jobs in the 1980s International Survey: Demographic Tables, Part 2, 1983 (Box 51:1188-1190)
      - Jobs in the 1980s International Survey, Appendix II: The German Professional Interviews, 1983 (Box 51:1191-1198)
      - "Retirement", 1980 Sep (Box 51:1199)
      - Golub, J., Work and Retirement for Older Americans, 1982 Dec (Box 51:1200-1202)
      - Greenough, W. C. and D. Yankelovich, Older Americans in the Workplace - executive summary, 1982 Nov (Box 51:1203)
      - Immerwahr, J., J. Golub and H. Laur, Childcare in the United States - executive summary - draft, 1982 Nov 19 (Box 51:1204)
      - Survey: Work in the 1980s and 1990s - A Series of Nine Articles Appearing in Working Woman Magazine, 198 (Box 52:1205)
      - Lauer, Harvey, Jobs in the 1980's and 1990's: A Sourcebook for Policymakers - draft, 198 (Box 52:1206-1211)
      - Lauer, Harvey, Jobs in the 1980's and 1990's: A Sourcebook for Policymakers, 198 (Box 52:1212-1215)
    - Work Ethic
      - Notes
        - General, 1982 (Box 52:1216-1217)
        - Industry, 1985 (Box 52:1218)
        - Jobs, 1984 (Box 52:1219)
        - Workplace statistics, [1981] (Box 52:1220)
        - Survey of worker attitudes, 1977 (Box 52:1221-1223)
        - Memorandum concerning worker typology, 1978 Jun (Box 52:1224)
        - Notebook: "The Work Ethic and Economic Recovery", [1982] (Box 52:1225)
        - Notebook: "Taylorism vs. High Discretion Model", [1982] (Box 52:1226)
        - Notebook concerning work ethic survey, [1982] (Box 52:1227)
      - Quality of life survey: Puget Sound, 1982 (Box 52:1228-1229)
      - Typescript draft, introduction #2, "Commitment to the Job," annotated, 1981 Sep 30 (Box 52:1230)
      - Handwritten draft: "A Great Debate", 1981 Nov 10 (Box 52:1231)
      - Paper on consensus in public opinion by D. Yankelovich, 1982 Mar 18 (Box 53:1232)
      - U.S. Chamber of Commerce survey on worker attitudes, 1980 (Box 53:1233)
      - Computer printouts of worker survey data, 1982 (Box 53:1234-1236)
      - Yankelovich, D. and J. Immerwahr, "Let's Put the Work Ethic to Work" Industry Week, vol. 218, no. 5, 1983 Sep 5 (Box 53:1237)
      - Yankelovich, D. and J. Immerwahr, "Putting the Work Ethic to Work" - Executive Summary, 1983 (Box 53:1238)
      - Yankelovich, D. and J. Immerwahr, "Putting the Work Ethic to Work," Society, 1984 Jan/Feb (Box 53:1239)
      - Public Agenda Foundation news release, 1983 Sep 5 (Box 53:1240)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 53:1241)
    - Related Material
      - Books, journal issues and reports
        - Carnevale, Anthony, Jobs for the Nation: Challenges for a Society Based on Work, 1984 (Box 53:1242)
        - Committee for Economic Development, Reforming Retirement Policies, 1981 Sep (Box 53:1243)
        - Council of Economic Advisors, Economic Indicators, 1982 Jan (Box 53:1244)
        - Datatrack, no. 1 - "Women", 1974 Summer (Box 53:1245)
        - Heineman, B., et al., Work and Welfare: The Case for New Directions in National Policy, 1987 (Box 53:1246)
        - Joint Ventures Between Business and Higher Education: Human Resource Evaluation - conference report, 1984 (Box 53:1247)
        - Lesieur, F.G., ed., The Scanlon Plan, 1958 (Box 53:1248)
        - Loftus, J. and B. Walfish, eds., Breakthroughs in Union-Management Cooperation, 1977 (Box 53:1249)
        - Mann, F., B. Indik and V. Vroom, The Productivity of Workgroups, 1973 (Box 53:1250)
        - Morse, S. W., Employee Education Programs: Implications for Industry and Higher Education, 1984 (Box 53:1251)
        - National Academy of Science, National Academy of Engineering, Institute of Medicine, High Schools and the Changing Workplace: The Employers' View, 1984 (Box 53:1252)
        - National Commission on Jobs and Small Business,, Making America Work Again, 1987 (Box 53:1253)
        - National Technical Administration Service, Industrial Psychology - A Bibliography with Abstracts, 1964-October, 1974, 1975 (Box 53:1254)
        - Psychology Today work survey - draft, 1978 (Box 53:1255)
        - Public Opinion work ethic issue, 1981 Aug/Sep (Box 53:1256)
        - Robison, David,, Alternative Work Patterns: Changing Approaches to Work Scheduling - conference report, 1976 (Box 53:1257)
        - United States General Accounting Office, Training Strategies - Preparing Noncollege Youth for Employment in the U.S. and Foreign Countries, 1990 (Box 53:1258)
        - U.S. Chamber of Commerce, Workers' Attitudes Towards Productivity, 1980 (Box 54:1259)
        - The Worklife Review, vol. 1, issue 1, 1982 Jul (Box 54:1260)
        - World of Work Report, vol. 6 no. 3, vol. 7, nos. 7-8, vol. 9, no. 2, 1981-1984 (Box 54:1261)
        - Yankelovich, Skelly, and White, Inc., A Business Perspective on Technological Innovation, 1980 (Box 54:1262)
        - YSW, Inc., Signal, A Continuing Study of Changing Work Values and Employee Motivations, 1979 (Box 54:1263-1264)
      - Book Chapters
        - Herrick, N. and M. Maccoby, "Humanizing Work: A Priority Goal of the 1970s" chapter 3 of Enhancing the Quality of Working Life, undated (Box 54:1265)
        - Leibenstein, H., "Microeconomics and x-efficiency theory: If there is no crisis there ought to be," chapter 6 of The Crisis in Economic Theory, undated (Box 54:1266)
        - Thurow, L. C., "Solving the Productivity Problem", undated (Box 54:1267)
        - "Trends in Work Values," chapter 2 of unknown work, ca. 1980 (Box 54:1268-1270)
      - Clippings
        - Journal articles, undated 1979-1983 (Box 54:1271-1272)
        - Periodical articles, 1981-1986 (Box 54:1273)
      - "Focus on Productivity" conference: papers and notes, 1981 Dec (Box 54:1274)
      - Forum 84, 1984 Jun (Box 54:1275)
      - Job Corps seminar, 1969 Mar (Box 54:1276)
      - Miscellaneous, 1982-1983 (Box 54:1277)
      - "New Subsidiary Benefit Plans Overview": slide presenation, 1983 (Box 54:1278)
      - Papers
        - Chamber of Commerce, "Productivity, People and Public Policy", [1981] (Box 54:1279)
        - Clarkson, W. and J. Gillespie, "The CEO's Impact on Productivity", 1981 Dec (Box 54:1280)
        - Etzioni, Amitai, "The New Industrial Age - Social, Economic Values and Occupational Context", 1981 Jan (Box 54:1281)
        - Etzioni, Amitai, "The Collaborative Society", 1984 (Box 54:1282)
        - Gartner, W. and J. Naughton, "The Deming Theory of Management", [1988] (Box 54:1283)
        - Gyllenhammar, P. G., "Needed: A People Based Labour Market Policy", 1980 (Box 54:1284)